感谢上帝 你们终于来了
Praise the gods, you've finally arrived
你比我想象中的要漂亮得多
and you are far more beautiful than I ever could have imagined.
什么?
Excuse me?
你不是来这里订婚的吧?
You have not come for the arranged marriage?
不是
No.
- 那是不是来找心上人呢?
- 不是
- Would you perhaps be seeking a husband?
- No.
那是什么风把你们吹到这里来了
Then what brings you to our town?
我们听说这里来了几个陌生人
We've heard of strangers who recently arrived
看起来很强悍 吹嘘杀死了很多幽灵
a rough-looking group, boasting of many Wraith kills?
我们觉得可能是Sateda人
Yeah, we think they might be Satedan.
噢 你是说那三个整日在酒馆
寻欢作乐的大嘴酒鬼?
Ah, yes, you mean the three loud-mouthed drunkards who spend their days carousing at the tavern?
听上去像是我的人
Sounds like my people.
他们在旅店开了几间房
They've taken rooms in the local inn.
- 谢谢
- 不用客气
- Thank you.
- You are most welcome
你真的没有考虑去找一个心上人么...
and should you ever reconsider your desire for a husband...
好吧 分头去找
我去旅店 你去酒馆
All right, I'll check the inn, you check the tavern
好主意
Sounds good.
你好
Hello?
我在找最近来这里的三个人
I'm looking for three individuals who recently arrived.
听说他们都很能吃喝
I've heard they are voracious eaters and drinkers, and
而且经常吹嘘自己曾打败过幽灵
apparently, they've been quite vocal about their recent successes against the Wraith.
你要找的那些人...
These people you're looking for...
他们要么是非常勇敢 要么是非常愚蠢
they're either very brave, or very stupid.
怎么说?
How so?
好吧
Well,
如果他们吹的牛皮传到幽灵的耳中
if word of their bragging got back to the Wraith
那对他们来说可就不妙了
it could be very bad for them.
我想他们不怕幽灵知道
I doubt they need to fear a Wraith overhearing their conversation.
当然不怕
Of course not,
可幽灵并不需要亲自听到
but the Wraith don't always need their own ears to hear.
你认识我要找的那几个人?
Do you know the people whom I seek?
抱歉
Sorry.
我从不多管闲事
I mind my own business,
也许你应该学着点
which is something you might want to consider.
还是把你的忠告
And you might want to consider offering
说给那些真正愿意接受的人听吧
your unsolicited advice to someone who actually cares to receive it,
你这种态度很容易招惹麻烦
An attitude like that could get you hurt,
或者更糟
or worse.
先割哪个?
What's the first to go?
耳朵? 还是那双漂亮的大眼睛?
The ears, or those pretty eyes?
你的脑袋怎么样?
How about your head?
Ronon!
Ara, Rakai!
听到传言没有?
Hmm, heard the rumor?
没有 什么传言?
No, what rumor?
算了 当我没说
Never mind. Forget I mentioned it.
等等 到底是什么?
Wait. What is this about?
不行 如果我现在说出来
就有点不负责任了
No, it would be irresponsible for me to say anything.
好吧 如果你非要我说
IOA已经做出决定了
All right, look, if you're going to twist my arm,
the I.O.A. have made their final decision.
他们已经选定Atlantis的新领导了
They've chosen the new leader of Atlantis.
是谁?
Well, who is it?
虽然还没有正式公告
Well, there's been no formal announcement, but
不过传言说那个人非常了解古人的科技
word is, they're going with their foremost expert in ancient technology
以及复制者
and Replicator activity.
你觉得这个人会是谁?
Who does that sound like to you?
- 你?
- 是啊 还能是谁?
- You?
- Yes. Who else?
我听说他们决定选一个
有科学研究背景的人...
Well, I heard they were leaning toward someone with a science background--
为什么不呢? 是时候让我们中的一员
来执掌真正的权力了
and why not? It's about time that one of us ended up in a position of real power.
噢 噢 你说的"我们" 指的就是"你"吧
Oh, oh, and by "us," you mean "you."
很对
Exactly.
还真有点紧张
It's kind of scary, though.
我将来所作的决定
不仅将会影响到这个城市
You know, I'll be making decisions that don't affect just the city,
还会影响到整个星系
but the entire galaxy.
是啊 紧张
Yes, scary.
- 非常紧张
- 不过换句话说
- Very scary
- On the other hand,
一名领导者从来不会预测自己的前途
a leader never second-guesses himself.
我要接受挑战
I'm up for the challenge.
我知道自己是谁
I know I am.
我会让他们自豪的
I'm going to make them proud.
Radek 我会让你感到自豪的
Radek, I'm going to make you proud.
幽灵和复制者正打得不可开交
The Wraith-Replicator war is in full swing.
从目前的情况来看
复制者正在攻击它们的最后一道防线
From what I hear, the Replicators are kicking some serious ass in their last offensive.
真是好消息 John
干得好
That's good news, John. Well done.
- 嗨!
- 我稍候把报告提交给你
- Hey!
- I'll have the reports ready for you.
Sam!
啊... 有什么新消息?
Uh... what's new?
为这里的权力交接做准备
Just making preparations for the change in command here.
不用你说 我已经知道了
You don't have to tell me. I already know.
真的?
Really?
我要说的是 IOA做了一个
再正确不过的决定
I just want to say that I think the I.O.A. could not have made a better choice.
谢谢 Rodney
Thanks, Rodney.
不不不 你太客气了
No, no, no, no, you are too kind.
什么?
What?
啊... "谢谢 Rodney"
Uh... "thank you, Rodney?"
等等 你是说...
No, no, wait a minute. You mean the...
是的 她是我们的新头
Yeah. She's our new boss.
星际之门 亚特兰提斯
第4季 第3集
Stargate Atlantis
Season 04 Episode 03
我还以为你们都死了
I thought you guys were dead.
信不信由你 我们也这样想过
Believe me, so did we.
在幽灵袭击Sateda的时候
你们是怎么幸存下来的?
How did you manage to survive the Wraith attack on Sateda?
我们不在那里
We weren't there.
我不明白
I don't understand.
我们最开始决定反击幽灵的时候
When we first made the decision to fight back against the Wraith,
没有等他们过来找我们
we didn't just wait for them to come to us.
而是率先对他们的几个据点发起了进攻
We started running ops against some of their known strongholds.
都是一些快战
They were quick strikes.
冲进去 痛宰他们 然后撤退
Get in, hit 'em hard, get out.
只有在那次 我们在撤退的过程中
出了点麻烦
Only on this particular occasion, we kind of messed up the getting out part.
我看到Dart飞船攻击了你们所在的位置
I saw the darts hit your position.
你没有看到的是我们在山中
找到了一个洞窟群落
What you didn't see was that we'd found a network of caves in the hillside.
幽灵攻击的时候
When the Wraith attacked
洞口塌了 我们被困在了里面
the entrance collapsed, and we were sealed in.
我们花了三天才挖开
It took us three days to dig our way out.
可那个时候 周围已经到处都是他们
And by then, the place was crawling with them.
很明显他们正在集结 准备下一波进攻
It was obvious they were gearing up for an attack.
我们又花了两周的时间才找到路
赶到星门那里 可那时...
Took another two weeks before we could find our way through the gate, and by then...
已经太迟了
it was too late.
等我们赶回Sateda的时候
已经什么都没有了
When we got back to Sateda, there was nothing left.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我不该丢下你们的
I should have never left you behind.
别傻了Ronon
Don't be an idiot, Ronon.
你带领第二小队回到星门那里的时候
When you took second squad back to the gate,
根本就不知道那些Dart飞船会来
you had no way of knowing those darts were going to come through
如果我们跟你回去
And if we'd have gone back with you
那也会跟其他人一样
在幽灵的袭击中死去
then we would have died in the attack on Sateda along with everybody else.
你能够生存下来的原因
The only reason why you survived
是因为他们让你成为一名Runner
was because they made you a runner.
你们已经听说了?
You heard about that?
回来后不久 我们就听到了一些传言
A while back, we started hearing stories.
他们说你有7尺高 力气赶得上5个人
They said you were seven feet tall and had the strength of five men.
人们都喜欢吹
People like to exaggerate.
他们还是你杀了一百个幽灵
They also said you killed a hundred Wraith.
这倒比较接近事实
That part sounds about right.
好吧...
Well, then...
为敌人的悲惨遭遇
to the misery of our enemies
为我们朋友的重聚
and the reunion of friends
为九死一生 干杯
come back from the dead.
好
Oh, yeah.
我离开Chulak的那天
On the day I left Chulak
Bratac跟我说
master Bratac said to me
"丢掉过去"
"draw from your past
"但不要让过去丢下你"
but do not let your past draw from you."
很好的忠告
That's good advice.
不过我还是很怀念这个地方
Still, I know I'm going to miss this place,
还有你们
and all of you.
虽然会引起你的不快 可我不得不说
I would have been offended had you felt otherwise.
十年可不短啊
10 years is a long time.
已经足足过了十年了
It has been 10 years well spent.
我们已经打败了不计其数的敌人
克服了无数险阻
We have defeated numerous enemies and overcome many threats.
一切都记忆犹新
It was never dull.
我们在这里获得了很多
We have accomplished much here,
可现在Atlantis需要你
but now it is Atlantis that is in need of you.
是啊...
Yeah...
一方面 我非常想去那里...
Part of me is looking forward to going, but...
可另一方面 又觉得这是不是太快了
you know, there's a part of me that thinks maybe it's too soon,
我这里的工作还没有完成
that I'm leaving my work here unfinished.
你的工作会继续完成的
Your work will continue
只是换一个地方而已
only in a different place.
你已经被赋予了无与伦比的荣誉
Carter上校
You have been bestowed an incredible honor, Colonel Carter,
我相信你会接受它的
and I believe you should embrace it.
记住...
And know this...
虽然我们不能跟你一起行动了
though we may not be leaving with you,
可SG-1就在你身边
SG-1 will never be far away.
这么说你们随时可以来做客了?
So I can expect you guys to come and visit sometime?
没有什么困难可以吓倒我
Undomesticated equines could not keep me away.
说得好
Nice call-back.
当然
Indeed
好了
All right.
该走了
Time to go.
这是什么?
What's that?
跟我们做交易的不同星球出产的水果
It's a selection of fruits from the various worlds we trade with.
我觉得这应该很有意义
I thought it'd be thoughtful.
真没劲
Try lame.
是么? 那你有什么建议?
Really, and what would you suggest?
也许该送些花
You know, maybe some flowers.
这样可以给她的房间增光不少
You could brighten up her quarters.
哦 送花
Oh, flowers.
给 拿着 走吧
Here, take this, and go.
Carter上校
Colonel Carter
欢迎来到Atlantis
welcome to Atlantis.
谢谢
Thank you.
很高兴到这里
It's nice to be here.
我想告诉你们 接到这个认命
我感到非常荣幸
I want you all to know how honored I am to accept this appointment.
我会尽全力领导好这支探险队
I've come here fully committed to this expedition,
为了Atlantis 更重要的是
为了你们每一个人
to Atlantis, and most importantly, to each and every one of you.
期望能跟你们一起工作
I look forward to working with all of you.
谢谢
Thank you.
说得好
Nice speech.
谢谢
Thank you.
我还主持过婚礼和颁奖典礼
I also do weddings and award shows.
事先拟好讲稿 才不至于让大家失望
Book early to avoid disappointment.
要不要去看看你的新住处?
Should we go check out your new digs?
好的
Yeah
Rodney...
Sam...
sam...
不痛么 轻点?
Stings, doesn't it?
你们三个这些年是怎么过的?
What the hell have the three of you been doing all these years?
噢
Oh
吃饭 喝酒
eating, drinking
杀幽灵
killing Wraith
我都记不清杀采取了多少次行动
We've hit 'em more times than I can count.
杀死的幽灵就更不用说了
Racked up a pretty nice body count.
更别提我们还干掉了12艘Dart飞船
Not to mention the 12 darts we've downed.
我们灵活 激动 而且有时
还可以收到很好的情报
we're armed, mobile, and, occasionally, get good intel.
听起来不错
Well, sounds like a pretty nice run.
不过还是有牺牲
But there have been a few sacrifices.
什么意思?
Yeah? What do you mean?
有五个人活着从山洞中走了出来
There were five of us who came out of that cave alive...
可在第一次袭击幽灵的时候
我们失去了Marika
but we lost marika on the first assault against the Wraith
然后去年我们又失去了Hemi
and then hemi last year.
一直都很艰难
It hasn't been easy.
我们的条件有限 可一直在坚持
We don't have much to work with, but we make do.
只是有些时候 只有这些还不够
Sometimes, it's not enough.
好吧 我也许可以帮忙
Yeah, well, I might be able to help.
我这里有人 装备
We've got the manpower, the equipment.
我和我的朋友们可以...
My friends and I, we can...
不管怎样...
anyway, um...
敬Marika和Hemi
to marika and hemi.
To marika and hemi.
敬Marika和Hemi
谢谢
Thank you
嘿 Rodney 进来
Hey, Rodney. Come on in.
我给你带了样可以装饰房间的东西
I brought you a little something to spruce up the place.
谢谢 很温馨
Well, thank you. That's very sweet.
那里有一个花瓶
There's a vase right there.
噢 那是Sheppard中校送来的
Oh, Colonel sheppard dropped that off.
看上去是跟我们有贸易关系的星球
上出产的各种水果
Apparently, it's a sampling of fruit from the home worlds of our various trading partners.
我觉得它们很有意义
I thought it was a really thoughtful gesture.
狗娘养...
son of A...
好吧
anyway
我来... 是为了欢迎你来到Atlatnis
look, I just... I just came by to welcome you to Atlantis,
看看你是不是都安排好了
see how you're settling in, and
还有看你是不是需要些什么
另外 我有没有提过跟某人谈过恋爱?
you know, if you needed anything, and did I mention I was seeing someone?
抱歉 什么?
I'm sorry, what?
我 跟某人谈过恋爱
I'm, uh, seeing someone.
我提起这个是因为你来了
Yes, I only bring it up now because you're here
我们会经常在一起工作
now and we'll be working together a lot more, and
我只是想起我们的过去...
you know, I just thought with our past...
我们的过去?
our past?
你知道 以前热恋的那种感觉
萦绕让在脑海中 一直无法忘怀
Well, you know, the unrequited lust that's been hanging over our heads for what seems like forever.
Rodney--
我只是不希望我们之间有什么难堪
I just don't want things to be awkward between the two of us, you know?
比如说现在...
kind of like they are now.
Rodney...
我可以保证 我们会好好相处的
I'm sure we'll be fine.
哦 当然 我是说 我会没事的
Oh, of course. I mean, I'll be fine. I'm just...
- 只是跟你在一起...
- 听说现在你是头
- with you...
- I hear you're in charge.
Ronon 这位是Carter上校
Sam 这位是Ronon 他是...
Ronon, this is Colonel Carter. Sam, this is Ronon. He's--
Sateda人
Satedan
同时也是你们小队的一员 我知道
and a member of your team. Of course.
有什么事么?
What can I do for you?
我想带一些朋友来Atlantis 当然
先要征求一下你的同意
I want to bring some friends to Atlantis, and, apparently, I've got to clear it through you first.
太不巧了 新的安全条例
Unfortunately, some new security procedures
不允许我在这个时候允许
外星访客来到Atlantis
prevent me from allowing any off-world visits to Atlantis for the time being.
是谁的命令?
On whose authority?
IOA的指示
It was a directive from the I.O.A.
那不告诉他们就行了
Well, they don't need to know.
Ronon 她是...
Ronon, she's--
我相信你很清楚我们现在的处境
I'm sure you understand what a precarious position we're in here.
不让基地的位置外泄是非常必要的
It is imperative that the location of this base remain a secret.
当然不会
And it will.
他们都是我的人 我可以为他们保证
They're my people. I'll vouch for them.
我知道你可以
I'm sure you can,
可现在 我们处于一个新的星球
就必须遵守新的条例
but for now, we're on a new planet with a new set of rules.
还有这里的新头
And a new person in charge.
Weir绝对不会怀疑我
Weir never would've doubted me.
OK 第一 Ronon
Okay, first of all, Ronon,
我不是在怀疑你
I'm not doubting you.
这个新条例适用于基地中的每个人
These new regulations apply to everyone on this base,
第二...
and secondly...
我不是Weir博士
I'm not dr. Weir.
他一直是这样么?
Is he always like that?
不...
No, no...
只是今天碰巧被你遇上了
no, actually, you caught him on a good day.
OK
Okay.
握在一起 转!
Try it together, and turn!
坚持住
Work on it.
速度很快啊
well, that was fast.
我说过会很快的
Yeah, I said it would be.
你不用这么赶忙的
You could have taken your time.
我们很喜欢这里
We like it here.
还想再多呆几天呢
We're thinking of staying on a few more days.
然后呢 去哪?
Then where will you go?
谁知道
Wherever
我们现在的好处就是无拘无束
That's one of the nice things about not being tied down.
可以去任何想去的地方
You go where you want,
呆厌了 就可以走
and you leave when you're not wanted.
我本希望我的人可以收留你们
可是...
Yeah, well, I was hoping my people would show a little bit more hospitality, but...
算了
don't worry about it.
我能理解
I understand.
不是所有人都可以去Atlantis
Not everybody gets an invitation to Atlantis.
不要感到奇怪
Don't look so surprised.
你跟我们一样 也在这个星系里
到处游历
You travel as much around this galaxy as we do
迟早你会听到传言 关于那些
住在古人以前城市中的人
and sooner or later, you'll start hearing rumors about new people in the city of the ancients
以及加入他们的那个Runner
and the runner who joined 'em.
抱歉
Man, I'm sorry.
我一开始就该跟你说实话的
I wish I could've been straight with you from the start.
他们信任你
They placed their trust in you,
而你也向他们证明 这种信任是值得的
and you proved them worthy.
这已经很不错了
I wouldn't have expected any less.
- 是啊 可是...
- 可是什么
- Yeah, but still--
- what
你指望因为是你在请求
他们就可以破一次例么?
you thought they'd make an exception because it was you asking?
- 我应该是他们的朋友才对...
- 不
- I'm supposed to be their friend--
- no.
你只是他们的同盟
You're their ally.
他们的客人
Their guest.
Rakai Ara 还有我 才是你的朋友
Me, rakai, and ara, we're your friends.
我一点也不怀疑 他们都是好人
I don't doubt they're good people.
他们在你需要的时候救你
They helped you out when you needed it
而且据我所知 他们比任何人
杀的幽灵都多
and from what I hear, they've done more to hurt the Wraith than anyone.
这一点你必须承认
You've got to respect that
可这并不意味着你要听从他们的指挥
but it doesn't mean you've got to commit to them.
就我来看
The way I see it,
现在我们又重新聚在一起了...
now that we're back together...
你应该属于我们
you belong with us.
很壮观 是吧?
Pretty impressive, isn't it?
老实说 有一点压抑
To be honest, it's a little overwhelming.
是不是因为有人向你说了什么
Coming from somebody with your record, that says something.
知道吗 John 你的名字
曾经出现在裁人名单上
You know, john, your name was on the short list.
是的 我知道
Yeah, I know.
我已经看到了他们对Elizabeth所做的一切
I saw what they did to Elizabeth,
那些政客 还有冠冕堂皇的说辞...
我并不嫉妒她
the politics and the red tape. I didn't envy her.
我也不嫉妒你
I don't envy you.
谢谢
Thanks.
在我们大多数人心中
You know, for most of us,
Elizateth的事情还没有完
this thing with Elizabeth isn't over yet.
她还在世上
She's still out there.
你真的认为她还会活着么?
You really believe there's a chance she's still alive?
只有一种办法可以肯定
There's only one way to know for sure.
你是说我们回去?
You're suggesting we go back?
我们本可以快点的
We should have done it sooner
可IOA总是阻止我
but the I.O.A.'S been stonewalling me.
现在是你说了算 也许你可以
给我开下绿灯
Now that you're in charge, maybe you can give me the green light.
抱歉 这太危险了
I'm sorry, but it's too dangerous.
可这不会比我们上一次更危险
It's no more dangerous than the last time we went in.
情况已经发生了变化 另外 上一次你们
具有一定的优势 可这次就不会有了
Circumstances were different. Plus, you had an advantage then that you don't have now.
上次的优势正是她给的
Well, she's the one who gave us that advantage.
没有她 我们也不会在这里
The only reason we're here is because of what she did.
相信我 这我都知道
Believe me, I know
而且跟你一样 我也绝对不会丢下
某个人不管
and I don't like the idea of leaving someone behind any more than you do
可我不会派你或者其他人去执行一个
自杀任务
but I'm not about to send you or anyone else on a suicide mission.
如果你能向我提交一个
有一丝成功希望的方案
Now, you come to me with a plan that has an even an outside chance of succeeding
我会重新考虑的
and I'll consider it.
一句话 John 我很抱歉
Short of that, john, I'm sorry.
我不能帮这个忙
There's nothing I can do.
好吧
Fair enough.
今天你分心了
You seem distracted today.
噢 不 我没事
Oh, no, I'm fine.
- 怎么了?
- 没什么 跟你说了 我没事
- What's wrong?
- There's nothing. I told you, I'm fine.
好吧 那我们就继续训练吧
Very well. I suppose we should just continue training.
真的没什么
There's nothing!
OK 别打我了
Okay, stop hitting me!
老天啊... 我说
God... I'll talk.
我打算离开Atlantis
I'm thinking of leaving Atlantis.
准备去哪儿?
Where would you go?
Atlantis和你的Sateda朋友之间
必须作出一个选择么?
Must it come down to a choice between Atlantis and your Satedan friends?
他们不仅仅是我的朋友 Teyla
他们是我的家人
They're more than my friends, Teyla. They're my family.
我们以前一直在一起的
We've always been there for each other.
你不会理解的
You wouldn't understand.
我不同意
I disagree.
我离开了我的Athosia族人 留在Atlantis
Leaving my fellow athosians for a home here on Atlantis
也是一个非常艰难的决定
was a very difficult decision.
我可是他们的头人
I was their leader.
对某些人来说
For some
是他们所知的唯一领袖
the only leader they'd ever known
即使我距离他们很近 穿过星门
就可以看到他们
and despite the fact that I was as close as a trip through the stargate
有些时候 我就感觉自己是背叛了他们
there were moments when I felt I'd betrayed them.
- 然后呢? 你适应了?
- 不
- So what? You got over it?
- No.
有些时候我认真考虑过这个决定
I sometimes still second-guess my decision
觉得我在这里可以为我的人民
以及这个星系中的其他人
then I remember that I can do more here to help my people
提供更多的帮助
and the rest of humans in this galaxy
而在我的母星则做不到
than I ever could on my home world.
Teyla已经跟你谈过了 是吧?
Teyla's already spoken to you, hasn't she?
是啊 我们小谈了一下
Yeah, well, we had a little chat.
说出来听听
So let's hear it.
说什么?
Hear what?
你想说的
Whatever you've got to say.
- 什么也不想说
- 是么?
- Not going to say anything.
- Really?
我没必要说 因为你已经知道了
我要说什么
I don't have to, because you already know what I'm going to tell you.
你是我小队中不可或缺的一员
That you're a valuable member of my team
很难找到其他人接替你的位置
and that it would be difficult to find somebody to take your place.
还有你认为可以回去找回曾经失去的东西
And that you may think you're going back to find something you've lost,
可没有什么能够找回的了
but there's nothing to go back to.
Sateda已经没有了 跟你那伙人一起流浪
也不会让它恢复
Sateda is gone, and living on the run with your buddies isn't going to bring that back.
你真的不愿意说出来?
You're not going to say any of that?
我没必要说
I don't have to.
听着 我这么做并不是想找回过去
Look, this isn't about me trying to bring back the past.
那到底是为什么?
Well, then what is it?
他们需要我
They need me.
一直都是
They always have.
我应该去照料他们
I'm the one that took care of them,
带领他们在战斗中生还
got them home alive whenever we went into battle.
你只有一个人 Ronon
You're one man, Ronon.
不能指望可以永远保护他们
You can't expect to protect them forever.
也许是不行
Probably not...
可你们追求的不也是这个么
but that's where you guys come in.
我们收到一条关于幽灵目标的情报
We got some intel on a Wraith target.
幽灵和复制者正打得不可开交
The Wraith and the Replicators are kind of beating the crap out of each other right now.
我想现在出击是很不明智的
I think it's counter-productive to run an op against them.
你听到情报的详细内容
就会改变主意的
I have a feeling you'll change your mind once you hear the details.
说说看
Let's hear it.
现在不行
Not yet.
我要Tyre Ara和Rakai都加入进来
I want tyre, ara, and rakai in on this.
你们准备袭击幽灵的实验室?
You want to hit a Wraith lab?
恕我冒犯 可现在谈论这个
No offense, but that's awfully close to
是不是有点疯狂
crazy talk territory
那是个武器研究机构
It's a weapons research facility.
据我们所知 那里人员配备
严重不足
From what we've heard, the place is undermanned
我们知道幽灵正在好
几条战线遭受攻击
We know the Wraith are being attacked on several fronts.
他们没有足够的资源来守卫
They don't have the resources anymore to properly guard all their facilities.
不过 她说的是"严重不足"
而不是"没有人"
Still, she did say, "undermanned" rather than "unmanned."
这两者区别很大
There is a big difference.
这不要紧 我们可以对付
It won't matter. We can handle it.
那为什么还需要我们帮忙?
Then why do you need our help to pull it off?
不需要
We don'T.
只需要在我们完事之后
把我们接出来
But we will need your help to get away once we're done.
明白了
I see.
我们成了你们的专职司机了
We're your designated drivers.
这就是我们的目标
This is our target.
距离星门有大半天的步行距离
It's located a good half day's journey from the gate on foot.
如果有飞船接应 就可以
赶到增援到来之前撤离那里
Having a ship would make things a whole lot easier getting us in and out before any reinforcements arrive.
别担心 你们只需要开好飞船就行了
Don't worry. All you got to do is fly.
其他事情交给我们来办
We'll do the legwork.
你们可真懂得体谅人啊
可如果我们同意
Well, that's very considerate of you, but if we commit,
就要参加整个行动
we're all in.
我真的不明白为什么要这么干
And I really don't see why we would.
当然 也许可以接触到一些幽灵的新科技
不过...
I mean, sure it would be great to get our hands on some new Wraith tech, but
也许我们可以偶然发现个存贮罐
或者买通ebay 不过...
maybe if we stumbled across a stockpile, or maybe bought some off of ebay, but--
他想要说的意思是
I think what he's trying to say is,
我们值不值得冒着生命危险
进行这次行动
we're not really sure if we want to risk our lives for something like this.
也许等一两个月
Maybe wait a month or two
复制者和幽灵之间打得差不多了
let the Replicators and the Wraith soften each other up
我们可以在午饭的时候再来谈这个
then we do lunch, we talk about it again.
他们在那个实验室所做的研究之一
就是如何关闭复制者的攻击指令
One of the things they're working on right now in the lab is a way to switch off the Replicator attack code.
这有可能么?
Is such a thing even possible?
那段指令以前也被关闭过
The code's been deactivated once before.
也许就是幽灵干的
The Wraith may have done it the first time.
那我们不能让这成为可能
Well, we can't let it happen.
不能
No.
如果和复制者之间的战斗结束了
If the war with the Replicators ends,
幽灵又会把注意力集中到
星系的其他星球上
then the Wraith will once again be able to direct their attention to the rest of the galaxy.
这么说...
So...
你们加入了?
are you in?
你的人看起来很精明能干
Your buddies seem like a perfectly capable enough bunch
可如果让我参加 最不愿意看到的就是
but if I do this, the last thing I need is
有人拖后腿 威胁到这次行动
someone going off half-cocked and risking this op
还有 我们自己的安全
and, well, oh, yeah, our asses.
这已经不是第一次了 John
This isn't their first time doing this, john.
不过这是第一次跟他们合作
May be the first time doing it with company
我不希望他们一上场就吓得尿湿裤子
though, and I don't want it turning into a big pissing match
好吧 那我来带我的人
你带你的人
Yeah, well, I'll keep my group in line. Do the same for yours.
我查过了 他们以前就是你的人
Last time I checked, it was your group, too.
是啊...
Yeah...
听着 我想跟你说的是
look, I was going to wait to tell you this,
我已经作出决定
but I've made my decision.
完成这次任务之后
Once we finish this op
我就要离开Atlantis
I'm going to be leaving Atlantis.
进来吧
Come on in.
收拾东西?
Packing?
是啊
Yeah
既然你把这些东西都带到这里来了
说明你已经把Atlantis当成自己的家了
You know, the fact that you brought all this stuff here tells me that you considered Atlantis home
你在这里很快乐
that you were happy here
是啊 曾经是
Yeah, well, I was.
现在也是
I am.
你的朋友们很担心你
Your friends are worried about you.
不需要 我会照顾好我自己的
Well, they shouldn't be. I can take care of myself.
我指的不是这个
That's not the point.
当你接受邀请加入Atlantis时
那已经是我们当中的一员了
When you accepted the offer to join Atlantis, you became a part of something
不管你愿不愿意 你的根已经扎到这里了
and, like it or not, you have roots here now
这里有关注你的人 有依靠你的人
people who care about you, who depend on you
就这么走开 可能比你所想象的要难
Walking away may be a lot harder than you think.
我不是想走开
Oh, I'm not walking away.
不是Sheppard小队中的一员
并不就意味着
Just because I'm not a part of sheppard's team does not mean
我不愿意帮助Atlantis 或者舍身帮助你们
I'm any less willing to help out Atlantis, or put my life on the line for any of you.
我并不是在怀疑你的衷心 Ronon
I'm not questioning your loyalty, Ronon,
只是觉得你这样走并不明智 正如你所说
你不想和Atlantis作对
only the wisdom in leaving, if, as you say, you don't want to turn your back on Atlantis.
同时照顾你和你的朋友们
可能不是那么容易
Coordinating our efforts with you and your friends may not be so easy.
那我们就慢慢来 不是么?
We're about to find out, aren't we?
希望你可以重新考虑离开的打算
I need you to reconsider your decision to leave.
如果我不呢
And if I don't,
说出我所知的关于Atlantis的一切
given everything that I know about Atlantis,
你会阻止我么?
you will try and stop me.
希望不要发展到那一步
I'm hoping it won't come to that.
把我们放到南边
Put us down near the south end.
从那里上去遇到的抵抗最小
We'll meet less resistance if we access this place through the back.
知道了
Got it.
进去之后 我们带路
Once we head in, we'll take the lead.
你们断后
You watch our backs.
你知道要去哪里么?
Do you know where you're going?
我们的目标在第二层的某处
Our target is located somewhere on the second level.
也许你可以说得更具体一点?
Uh, maybe you could be a little more specific?
如果你要问的话 那我得说
我们没有那么详细的计划
We don't have an exact floor plan, if that's what you're asking.
整个第二层都是高度保密的
The whole second level is a high-security sector.
如果你们不是很确定的话 让我们跟着
效率不是有点低么?
If you are unsure, would it not be counter-productive for us to follow you?
最好这样
It's better this way.
幽灵的建筑都非常复杂
These Wraith facilities are very confusing.
我们知道要找什么
We know what we're looking for.
我们就不知道?
Oh, and we don't?
这又不是我们的第一次行动
This isn't exactly our first op, you know.
是么?
Really.
在面对面的交战中 你干掉过
多少个幽灵?
How many Wraith have you killed in hand-to-hand combat?
我看不出这有什么关系
I hardly think that's what this is about.
- 我就知道你会这么说
- 知道么 我们干掉过整艘的幽灵母舰
- That's what I thought.
- You know, we've taken out entire hive ships, okay?
跟我们相比 你们都是业余的
Compared to us, you are amateurs.
别紧张
Easy.
如果我们不能很好合作的话
If we can't play nice together,
那就不要合作了
then let's not.
我们短时间内要搜索很大一片区域
We got a lot of ground to cover in a short amount of time, so
我们会先跟在你们后面
we will follow your lead.
到达第二层后分开行动
Then we'll split up into two teams once we reach the second level.
你们可以接受吗?
Are you cool with that?
是的
Yes
好
Good
接近目标
Approaching target location.
就是这里
This is it.
快点!
Hurry up!
我来
I got it.
都进去
Everybody in.
我们走这边
你们走那边
We'll go this way. You go that way.
如果你们找到什么就联系我们
Contact us if you find anything.
行
Yeah
祝好运
Good luck.
Ronon...
我们走
let's go.
你怎么想?
What do you think?
他们是试验对象还是幽灵版的
"自动贩卖机"里的货物?
Test subjects? Or the Wraith version of a vending machine.
我很不愿意这么说
但是我们不能帮助他们
I hate to be the guy to say it, but we can't really help these people.
我们得继续走
We got to keep moving.
对
Right
这太安静 太容易了
This thing's been way too quiet and way too easy.
我喜欢这样简单安静的行动
偶尔换换口味也不错
I kind of like quiet and easy. Makes for a nice change.
幽灵!
Wraith!
Ronon 等一下!
Ronon, wait!
Rodney 把那扇门弄开!
Rodney, get that door open!
该死的门
the hell with it.
拜托 怎么他这样干就可以!
Aw, come on, it worked for him!
哈 我成功了!
Hah! I did it!
哦 谢天谢地 是你们
Oh, thank god, it's you three.
他们抓住了Teyla和Sheppard 而且...
They got Teyla and sheppard, and--
带他来
bring him.
现在谁是门外汉?
Who's the amateur now?
Ronon 发生了什么?
Ronon, what happened?
我要马上见Carter上校
I need to talk to Colonel Carter right away
John 你没事吧?
John, are you all right?
还有点后遗症
Bit of a hangover.
Ronon和他的朋友不在这是个好预兆
The fact that Ronon and his buddies aren't here is a good sign.
那不一定
Not really.
是Ronon的朋友引我们来的
他们设计了我们
Ronon's buddies are the reason we're here. They set us up.
你说什么?
What are you talking about?
我撞见他们的时候我正要逃...
I ran into them while I was trying to esc--
我正要进行战略性撤退
while I was effecting a strategic retreat.
他们把我击昏了
They stunned me.
你确定?
Are you sure?
这种事要理解很困难
It's pretty hard to misinterpret something like that.
Ronon和他们在一起吗?
Was Ronon with them?
我没看见他
I didn't see him.
那一个
That one.
等一会 伙计们
Hold on, here, guys.
Rodney...
坚持住 Rodney!
stay strong, Rodney!
我会试试
I'll try.
我说过我没事
I said, I'm fine.
我试过无线电联系Sheppard
但是他们没有一个响应
I tried to radio sheppard, but got no response from him, Teyla, or mckay.
那么那些Sateda人呢?
And what about the Satedans?
我们分开了
We got separated.
我想幽灵把他们也抓住了
I'm guessing the Wraith got to them, too.
看来这次行动没那么简单
So much for this op being a cake-walk.
那么...
Okay
我们由后备支持变成了救援队
we've gone from support to rescue and recovery.
Zelenka博士 准备一艘Jumper
Dr. Zelenka, ready a jumper
是的 上校
Yes, Colonel.
他们知道我们要来
They'll be expecting us.
准备两艘吧
Make that two jumpers.
你们能告诉我这是去哪吗?
Would you guys mind telling me where we're going?
老实说 我不是很喜欢惊喜
Seriously, I'm not big on surprises.
即使是小的时候 我都得偷偷看看
圣诞礼物因为我受不了那个惊喜
Even as a kid, I had to sneak a peek at my christmas presents because I couldn't stand the suspense.
- 我记得有一次...
- 我们需要你的说明
- I remember this one time--
- we require your assistance.
帮什么?
With what?
你修改了复制者的底层代码
You tampered with the Replicator base code.
我不知道你在说什么
I don't know what you're talking about.
好吧 我是做了几个小调整
那又怎么了?
Okay, I may have made a few small adjustments. So what?
这已经不是他们第一次攻击我们了
This is not the first time they have challenged us.
就是说是幽灵解除了那段指令
So it was the Wraith that deactivated the attack code.
几千年以前...
Many thousands of years ago.
我们击败了古人
成了这个宇宙的霸主
We had defeated the ancients. The galaxy was ours, and then these...
然后这些"东西"出现了
things appeared.
- 我猜你们的关系不太好...
- 他们是令我们极其厌恶的东西!
- I take it you're not a big fan--
- they are an abomination!
他们甚至都不是生命
They're not even alive.
也就是说你们不能以他们为食
所以他们对你们不是什么好东西
In other words, you can't eat them, so they're no good to you.
他们是机器
They are machines.
机器可以被重新程序设计
Machines can be reprogrammed.
好吧 那...
你要我干什么?
Okay, fine, so, what do you want from me?
我们尝试过再次上传解除程序
We have attempted to upload the deactivation virus once again.
但是我们失败了
Our attempts have been unsuccessful.
我们需要你撤销你做的更改
以使我们的程序再次产生效果
We need you to undo the changes you made so as to render the virus once more effective against them.
当然 我理解
Of course. I see.
但是 这可能会很困难
Things is, that could be kind of tricky.
这个试验对象会让事情简单一点
The test subject will make things easier for you.
试验物件?
Test subject?
一个复制者
A Replicator.
我的天哪
Oh, my god.
我已经考虑过了
我想告诉你当时机成熟的时候
I've thought about it, and I want you to know that when the time comes,
我会尊重你对你们的未来
做的一切决定
I'll respect whatever decision you make regarding your future with us.
这应该是我们第一次 也是最后一次
一起行动的机会了
This could be the one and only op we go on together.
那么我们最好让这次行动更有意义
Then we'd better make the most of it.
Mckay博士...
Dr. Mckay...
工作进度如何?
how is your work progressing?
有点慢
It's been kind of slow.
将底层代码还原到原始的设置
并不是很快就能完成的
I mean, re-establishing the base code's original setting isn't something I'll be able to accomplish overnight.
Sheppard和Teyla听到这个消息
一定会很沮丧
Colonel sheppard and Teyla will be most disappointed to hear this.
我保证
I'll see to it.
我想我可能能快点搞好
I think I might be able to get it finished much sooner.
我理解你在拖延 以给你的朋友
准备救援的时间
I understand your desire to delay in the hope that it will give your people time to mount a rescue.
事实上 我刚刚收到消息
他们就在路上
In fact, I've just received word they're on their way,
但是我们已经准备好了
but we are ready for them.
好的 他们已经离开了
Okay, they're moving away.
谢谢 二号Jumper
Thank you, jumper two.
我们进去吧 上尉
Take us in, lieutenant.
是 上校
Yes, Colonel.
快 快!
Let's go, let's go!
这堵墙后面有一个能量中继器
There's a power relay behind this wall here.
- 你们都没事吧?
- 时间正好
- You all right?
- Well, it's about time.
要是再迟一点 我们就要自救了
Any longer, we would've had to save ourselves.
Ronon有回到Atlantis吗?
Did Ronon manage to make it back to Atlantis?
- 是的
- 他在哪?
- He did.
- Where is he?
我们分开行动了
We split up to cover more ground.
守住门口 我们走
Secure the entrance. Let's go.
快点 我们离开这
All right, come on, let's get out of here.
你把他们关在哪了?
Where are you holding them?
为什么不问你的朋友?
Why don't you ask your friends?
安全了
All clear.
安全了? 你差点打到我!
All clear? You could've shot me!
哦 不
Oh, no.
哦 不要...
Oh, no...
我们去找Ronon
Let's go find Ronon.
你们来处理
Deal with him.
你们是幽灵的崇拜者?
You're Wraith-worshipers?
- Ronon 请你理解...
- 他们毁了整个Sateda!
- Ronon, you need to understand that--
- after what they did to Sateda!
Sateda已经没有了
我们所认识的人也一起没有了
Sateda is gone and so are the lives we knew.
我们别无选择
We had a choice
要么同过去一起死去 要么为了未来
而活着
to die with the past, or live for the future.
他们给了你们什么?
What did they do to you?
他们给我们的报酬就是来世的生命
They rewarded us with the gift of everlasting life.
你也可以得到这种恩赐
只要你愿意
The same gift can be yours, if you're willing to accept it.
开头我们也顽固不化
We resisted at first, we were stubborn,
可是幽灵已经下定决心
but the Wraith were determined.
他们向我们展示自己的未来
They showed us our futures.
让我们经历生命的终点
将我们推向边缘
They allowed us to experience  our life's end,  pushing us to the brink
让我们看清真相
so that we could see the truth,
然后将我们拉回来
and brought us back
然后又一次 再一次...
They showed us again,  and again, and again...
直到攻破你们的防线
until they broke you.
直到我们最终接受了事实
Until we finally accepted the truth
接受他们的恩赐
and their gift
Ronon...
加入我们吧
join us.
你们都疯了
You're insane
抛弃那无用的尊荣吧
Don't let your pride get in the way.
不要像Marika和Hemi那样
Like marika and hemi.
他们不是在行动中阵亡的 是不是?
They didn't die on any run, did they?
他们不愿意接受转变所以才被杀害了
They were murdered because they wouldn't turn.
他们被杀完全是因为自己的固执
They were killed by their own stubbornness.
不要犯同样的错误
Don't make the same mistake.
- 加入我们!
- 不
- Join us!
- No.
不可能
Never.
滚 你们滚吧
Run. You run.
滚得越远越好 因为我们再见面时
就不再是朋友了
Run, and get away while you can, because the next time we meet, it will not be as friends.
不会有下一次了
There won't be a next time.
我们要用Sateda人的方式
来结束这一切
We'll finish this like true Satedans.
你们不配做Sateda人
You are not Satedans!
Rakai 不!
Rakai, no!
这就是你们的尊荣?
So much for honor.
不要用武器
No weapons.
我们的杀戮还少么?
Hasn't there been enough killing?
啊?
Huh? 
Ronon 你的朋友们呢?
Ronon, where are your friends?
他们就在这里
They're right here.
我们回家吧
Let's go home.
那是我的画么?
Is that my painting?
是的
Yes.
Rodney觉得应该还给你
Rodney felt that you should have it back.
我又没有送给他
I didn't give it to him.
他是自己拿走的 以为是你不要的
Well, he helped himself, assuming that you were leaving it behind.
感觉怎样?
How you feeling?
还好
all right
很高兴你能回来
It's nice to have you back.
谢谢
Thanks
回来的感觉真好
It's good to be back